Serge Durand

Software Engineer and Full Stack Developer

- https://serge.codes https://linkedin.com/in/ sergedurand205

SUMMARY

Pragmatic and experienced software engineer who is well-versed in technology and writing code to create reliable and user-friendly systems that solve interesting problems. I'm also a skilled leader who has proven the ability to educate and manage a team of professionals to build software.

EXPERIENCE

Open Source Maintainer

10/2022 - Present

URL Shortener - tinyy.ink | youtu.be/xX9J4LlkRl8

- Developed an open-source project that convert long links into shorter ones. It supports QR code generation and statistics with chart.js
- A Redis-based cache server is used for high-performant and near real-time reads.
- Uses CAPTCHA to enhance security by preventing bots and DOS attacks.

Senior Javascript Developer

06/2022 - 08/2022

Thesis Follow up - edc-stg.online | tinyy.ink/stg-demo

- I led a team of developers in the development of a platform for following up the thesis of postgraduate students in my university. The tech stack consists of Mongodb, Expressjs, React & Nodejs (MERN)
- Implemented a robust API for front and backend communication and raised throughput of CORS requests by over 30%.
- My sharp project management and Agile development skills permitted the project to be completed a week prior to its pre-assigned completion date. I used Jira to track issues and tasks.

Software Developer 12/2019 - 03/2022

TechnigConsulting

- Worked in a software development agency where I took part in developing tailored software according to clients' business requirements.
- Collaborated with product managers to re-architect a multipage web-app to a single page app, boosting yearly revenue by over 30%.
- Tested software for bugs and operating performance, added documentation and fixed bugs to increase efficiency by 15%.
- Suggested using the appropriate technologies and tools per project which in turn increased time to production by over 2
 weeks.

Python Developer 06/2021 - 10/2021

CS Portal - camerschools.site | youtu.be/6LdmxpaATBs

- Developed a platform that offers many services to users such as a marketplace, Q/A section and discussion section, among others.
- It is deployed on the cloud with a microservices architecture backed by Docker and DBMS based on Postgres, all sitting on a Django implementation.

EDUCATION

Computer Science 2022

University of Yaoundé 1 - Bachelor's degree

• I led a team that developed a platform for my university to follow up the thesis of postgraduate students.

CERTIFICATES

DevOps Essentials (IBM) 11/2022 - Present

Enslish Speaking - Expert (Emmersion) 12/2022 - 04/2023

SKILLS

Docker Reactjs & Nextjs

CI/CD & DevOps Nodejs & Expressjs Python & Django SQL & NoSQL

JavaScript & TypeScript

Project Management

LANGUAGES

English Native French Native